# Haroldo Velez Lora

Machine Learning engineer, life-learner and team player. Three years of experience shipping to production machine learning and statistical models on cloud/web. I take pride in having built autonomous systems that are maintainable, scalable, resilient and adaptable (given the ML component).

105 The Queensway M6S 5B5 Toronto, ON +1 647 895 0752 hvelez020@gmail.com

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Bearing AI, Machine Learning Engineer

2022/08 - 2023/02

Led the development of a data-intensive system that needed to ensure robustness and reliability in the output information for a client that represented the 70% of the revenue of the company.

Managed expectations and project timeline with stakeholders to successfully deliver a good product to the client.

The system led to the client signing an extension of the contract for a year with the company.

### Mercado Libre, Machine Learning Engineer

2021/03 - 2022/08

Led the work with business owners and managers to design and ship an autonomous A/B testing agent to automatically set prices for insurance products of the company. Owned the whole system end-to-end.

Encouraged the team to implement good software and security practices by doing thorough code reviews.

The system led to an increase of 9.5% in the revenue of the company.

# Rappi, Machine Learning Engineer

2019/10 - 2021/02

Led the work with product owners and tech leads to design, ship, and refine the Machine Learning System for implementing query classification and ranking models into a productive search engine while ensuring scalability and maintainability.

Owned (build and maintain) search ranking microservices and Apache Airflow instance where ETLs were built.

The system led to a 20% increase in the conversion rate.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Universidad del Norte, B.Sc. in Electronics Engineering

2014/01 - 2019/03

My degree has an ABET accreditation.

### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, Go, SQL

Frameworks: NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, FastAPI, Airflow, Confluent, Elastic, Echo

Tools: Docker, Apache Airflow, Astronomer, Apache Kafka, Redis, PostgreSQL, Snowflake, Bigquery, Linux, AWS, Elasticsearch

Special Knowledge: Data
Analysis, Applied Statistics,
Machine Learning,
Distributed & Parallel
Computing, Data
Modelling, Web
Development, Big Data
Architecture, Database
Management, REST API.